Ian G. Speden Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Ian G. Speden Archives
1956-1965
IPAR.001128
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
5
The archives of Ian G. Speden including maps related to his Yale dissertation, "Paleozoology of Lamellibranchia from the type area of Fox Hills Formation, (Maestrichtian), South Dakota."
Speden, Ian Gordon
Biographical Sketch
Yale PhD 1965, Title: South Dakota collector.
Description of the Material
IP to fill out this scope and content
Connecticut; South Dakota; USA; Maps; Field notebooks; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Maps, 1951-1956; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Topographic maps of South Dakota.
  - 1951. Topagraphy maps of South Dakota from 1951., 001132
    - Topographic map. Dupree NE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001682
    - Topographic map. Redelm NE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001705
    - Topographic map. Redelm NW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001707
    - Topographic map. Ridgeview NE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001709
    - Topographic map. Ridgeview NW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001711
    - Topographic map. Thunder Butte, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001713
    - Topographic map. Trail City SW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1951; 001715
  - 1952. Topagraphy maps of South Dakota from 1952., 001133
    - Topographic map. Glencross SE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001686
    - Topographic map. Lantry NE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001689
    - Topographic map. Lantry NW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001691
    - Topographic map. Parade NE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001701
    - Topographic map. Parade NW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001702
    - Topographic map. Whitehorse, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1952; 001745
  - 1956. Topagraphy maps of South Dakota from 1956., 001134
    - Topographic map. Bullhead, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001729
    - Topographic map. Bullhead SW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001730
    - Topographic map. Black Horse, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001731
    - Topographic map. Black Horse NE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001732
    - Topographic map. Black Horse SE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001733
    - Topographic map. Little Eagle, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001734
    - Topographic map. Little Eagle NW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001735
    - Topographic map. Little Eagle SE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001736
    - Topographic map. Little Eagle SW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001737
    - Topographic map. Miscol, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001738
    - Topographic map. Miscol NE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001739
    - Topographic map. Miscol SE, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001740
    - Topographic map. Miscol SW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001741
    - Topographic map. Wakpala, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001742
    - Topographic map. Wakpala NW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001743
    - Topographic map. Wakpala SW, SD 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1956; 001744
  - Tracings. Tracings of South Dakota Topographic maps., 001135
    - Topographic map. Long's Ridge, SD (1: 62500). Speden, I.G.: Tracing., 001911
    - Topographic map. Long's Ridge, SD (1: 31250). Speden, I.G.: Tracing., 001912
    - Topographic map. Long's Ridge, SD (1: 31250). Speden, I.G.: Tracing., 001913
- Notebooks, 1962; Series II
  - South Dakota. Field notebooks from Fox Hills South Dakota., 001136
    - Notebook. Field notebook #1, type Fox Hills Fm: South Dakota., 1962; 000290
    - Notebook. Field notebook #2, type Fox Hills Fm: South Dakota., 1962; 000291
    - Notebook. Field notebook #3, type Fox Hills Fm: South Dakota, North Dakota. 1962, 1963, 000292
- Miscellaneous, Series III
  Miscellaneous archives including faulal lists and dissertation documents.
  - Dissertation. Copy of Ian G. Speden's dissertation and supporting figures., 001138
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints of Speden's dissertation bivalves. YPM 36073. Black and white prints and negatives, 000599
    - Tables 1-27, listed in Speden dissertation and YPM Bull. 33 (p. 26) as being on open file in Invert. Paleo. Division. 1965; 1970, 000509
  - Faunal List., 001137
    - Faunal list of Speden, Cretaceous, Mesaverde-Mancos, Colorado., 1965; 000797
- Locality Information, Series IV
  Locality information
  - Slides of localities. Color slides of localities with their field positions plotted on maps., 001323
    - Photographs. color slides taken by Ian Speden, with list slides and their field locations plotted on maps; Fox Hills Fm, S & N Dakota, 1962, 1963, 000970